A governor. A stripper. Forced to chose between the office he
held and the woman he loved, he chose both.
Blaze is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Ron Shelton.
A middle-aged Louisiana governor falls in love with a young stripper, which jeopardizes his
political career and the radical policies which have made him a controversial figure.
Gov. Earl K. Long, played by Paul Newman.
Blaze Starr, played by Lolita Davidovich.
Thibodeaux, played by Jerry Hardin.
LaGrange, played by Gailard Sartain.
Eldon Tuck, played by Jeffrey DeMunn.
Doc Ferriday, played by Garland Bunting.
Blaze is a 1989 American comedy-drama film written and directed by Ron Shelton, based on the 1974
memoir Blaze Starr: My Life as Told to Huey Perry by Blaze Starr and Huey Perry.
The film stars Paul Newman as Earl Long and Lolita Davidovich as Blaze Starr.
At the 62nd Academy Awards in 1990, the film received a
nomination for Best Cinematography for Haskell Wexler.
It was Wexler's fifth and final nomination, previously
winning for Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf?
(1966) and Bound for Glory (1976).
The film explores themes of governor, louisiana, civil rights,
stripper, based on memoir or autobiography.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.